## **AMIT RATHI**

Mobile # 9880416852, 6369171697 Email: amit\_rathi12345@yahoo.co.in

## Summary

Over 15 years of experience in IT service industry including 11 years of experience on PeopleSoft HCM Analysis, Design and Testing on various PeopleSoft HCM modules as NA Payroll, Base Benefits, Benefit Administration, Time and Labor, Core HR, ESS, MSS. Also got a chance to explore Workday application over the period of 9 months and having a good experience in managing, mentoring, and setting up new teams.

## **Highlights**

Technical Skills – SQL, PS Query,

Domain Knowledge - HRMS, Banking

Application & tools – AQT, HPQC, Jira-Zephyr, iDB, MovelT, SQL developer, OEMS, ALS, Lotus notes, and Custom Applications

ERP Applications - PeopleSoft and Workday

### **Experience**

Business Analyst Wipro Ltd. – Chennai Mar 2016 to till date

**Project Profile**: Supported PeopleSoft HCM project to implement CR then supported Workday implementation and data conversion and currently supporting Custom application as a Business Analyst to automate different business processes.

### Responsibilities:

### **Custom Application:**

- Providing solution to automate business processes.
- Creating SDD, Functional design document, DDL, UI screen design, configuration data and other supporting documents
- Working closely with business and development team to implement the requirements
- Testing the implemented functionality and supporting UAT.

## Workday Implementation and Data conversion project responsibilities:

- Current state Integration's requirement provided to the Workday team and involved in the discussion of future state requirements.
- Verified the WD requirements with the current state requirements to make sure all the business rules are covered.
- Responsible to execute end to end integration testing in Workday tenant.
- Logging the defects in Zephyr if the integration results are not matching the requirements.
- Supporting data conversion from PeopleSoft to Workday.
- Running program and validate the PeopleSoft data extracts against the workday mapping and validation rules.
- Providing resolution to fix the DC extracts to meet the needs of loading the data into workday

## PeopleSoft HCM 9.1 Support project responsibilities:

- Requirement gathering, analyzing, and providing the appropriate solution to the client
- Provide detailed solution estimates with project scoping and timelines
- Preparing project plan or CR implementation plan to implement a CR following a SDLC process
- Prepare resource modeler and align recourses for each phase to implement a CR
- Coordinating with client, technical team, testing team and other impacted domains to implement the CR as per planned timelines

- Creating BRDs for the new requirements and updating the existing BRDs as required
- Coordinating with the clients and other stakeholders in order to getting the approvals on detailed solution, BRDs and UAT test results.
- Identifying High level Test Scenarios, creating Use cases
- Maintaining RTM to make sure all the requirements have been covered in implementation
- Analyzing defects, finding root cause and provide solutions to fix it
- Supporting QA, IAT and UAT testing

## Sr. Software Engineer Tech Mahindra Ltd. – Bangalore

Dec 2013 to Feb 2016

**Project**: PeopleSoft HCM upgrade from 8.3 to 9.1 where in I have involved in NA Payroll, Benefits and Core HR Functional Testing

- Analyzing and Understanding the user requirements and specification
- Performing various testing: Functional, System integration, Compatibility testing.
- Identifying High level Test Scenarios, Test Cases and designing detailed test scripts
- Regression testing for all CRs and SRs
- Executing Test cases and updating test results in HPQC
- Tracking and updating defect status in Quality Center
- Writing SQL Queries for the data analysis and validation
- Carrying out functional testing of all delivered and custom functionality
- Interacting with client based on the issue faced and priorities of issue to be solved
- Testing and Signing-off new CR or modified elements to the Production environment
- Production deployment hyper care issues resolution Testing
- Discussing issues with technical team and leads in Daily SR review calls
- Helping team members in understanding the functionality and testing

#### Achievements:

Created macros to automate some manual reports which saves a lot of time

## Payroll Consultant Titan Technology Partners - Pune

Feb 2012 to Nov 2013

**Project**: NA Payroll implementation and Support project

- Testing any change request before migration into production environment
- Testing tax updates to ensure the integration of the system with the new delivered patches and functionalities
- Coordinating with the client and other departments to complete the payroll processing smoothly and on time
- End to end payroll processing on PeopleSoft application
- Research work on paycheck related queries
- Worked on Balance adjustments in the system
- Worked on W2, W4 forms
- Off-cycle checks and Final checks creation for the employees
- Analyzing payroll reports to ensure everything is going correct
- Validation of payroll by running post payroll reports
- Monitoring exception employee's paycheck to ensure that they would pay correct
- Resolving employee's queries regarding their earnings, deductions, taxes, vacation balances etc.
- Coordinating with the technical team in case any change is required in set up
- Developing PS gueries as per the requirement
- Creating Excel to CI template and Uploading mass data into system and validating it

#### **Achievements:**

- Supported 36 hours continuously for getting a critical issue resolved in payroll at the time of Go live
- Within a short duration, trained a helpdesk team of 20 people for PeopleSoft HCM Fundamentals

# Sr. Process Executive Infosys BPO Ltd.

Aug 2009 to Jan 2012

Project: PeopleSoft HCM project to handle company Benefits, Time & Labor and NA Payroll processing

- Monitoring the queue and allocating the cases amongst the team based on priority, TAT and SLA's
- Handling Client calls and escalations
- Providing Process training to the new associates
- Auditing of the transactions, done by the team members
- · Giving feedback to the team members
- Preparing SOPs for the processes and updates it according to the requirements
- Preparing different type of reports in excel
- Preparing monthly dashboard of the process
- Discussing weekly review call with the clients
- Handling benefits provided by the organization and enrolling employees into different plan types as per the eligibility criteria and as per the qualifying event
- COBRA Enrollment Processing
- FMLA Process and creating FMLA letters to the employees
- Preparing Injury Reports on Lotus Notes Application
- Calculating PTO hours for the employees and updating in the system
- Run Interfaces and different types of reports in the PeopleSoft
- Handling Time and labor process and resolving the setup related exception
- On-cycle and off cycle processing of Pay-checks
- Developing Queries to fetch the required data for the purpose of process improvement and accuracy

#### Achievements:

 Successfully completed a yellow belt project to reduce the number of clarification emails goes to the client

## Sr. Process Executive Infosys BPO Ltd.

Sep. 2007 to July.2009

Project: - Banking and capital market

- Working with the consumer lending process of Auto Loans
- Verify documents NOL and Title before granting the loan
- · Check for the missing documents and sending notification letter to the customer
- Notify department of vehicle regarding the lien condition of the vehicle and get the lien registered in the name of bank
- Researching for wrongly matched titles and manually correcting them in the system.
- Researching and issuing a letter to the concerned department for releasing the lien after closing the loan
- Dealing with the online Banking processes as ACH, Payment history, Amortization schedule
- Creating mail-merge letter template for follow-up and notification to the customers
- Providing process training to the new team members
- Preparing MIS report to show individual team member performance

Internal QC and audits for all sub processes

#### Achievements:

- Quickly learnt the process in short span of time and started working on production environment
- Completed MBA Full time course with 1st division, while doing job in night shifts

#### Education

S.No.	Qualification	Year of Passing	Board / University	Percentage
1	MBA-IT (Full time)	2010	Gyan Vihar University, Jaipur	62.00%
2	B.Sc. (Maths)	2006	M.D.S University, Ajmer	56.54%
3	12 <sup>th</sup>	2003	Rajasthan Board	65.38%
4	10 <sup>th</sup>	2001	Rajasthan Board	75.00%

#### **Achievements**

- 1 Year Diploma in computers: 'O' Level from DOEACC Society
- Infosys- individual Extra Miler Award-2 Times and SPOT Award-4 times (Monthly Performance Award)
- TTP Technology Employee of the month 2 Times and SPOT Awards 2 Times
- Tech Mahindra 2 Times Spot Awards
- Merit Recognition certificate by NIIT (Secured place in Top 9% of students) Jan 2007
- 1 Yellow Belt Project (To Reduce the % of e-mail Clarification)

#### Skills:

- HCM Functional
- SQL
- Advance Excel Modeling
- Good Analytical Skills
- Business Requirement Analysis
- Requirement Gathering

- System Testing
- Training end user
- Test case Documentation
- QA Expert
- User Acceptance Testing
- People Management